{
    "tossups": [
        {
            "question": "This poet wrote about \u201c[his] body, savage and peasant, undermining you\u201d in one poem before admitting he was \u201clonely as a tunnel.\u201d In one poem by this author, the speaker describes the title objects as being made from \u201cthreads of / twilight / and goatskin.\u201d This author wrote in another poem how \u201cterrible and brief was my desire for you!\u201d This poet described an object that \u201clived / through the sea\u2019s truth\u201d and in that same collection described a \u201ctender hearted\u201d (*) vegetable. This poet of \u201cBody of a Woman\u201d described \u201ccold flower heads raining over [his] heart\u201d in a poem in which he declares, \u201cOh pit of debris, everything fell into you!\u201d This author included a poem about his socks in his Elemental Odes, and in one poem he laments, \u201cIn you everything sank!\u201d For 10 points, what Chilean poet wrote Twenty Love Poems and a Song of Despair?",
            "answer": "Pablo Neruda [or Ricardo Eli\u00e9cer Neftal\u00ed Reyes Basoalto]",
            "subcategory": "Poetry",
            "category": "Literature"
        },
        {
            "question": "A character in this novel is sent to the United States to get a degree in Ornamental Gardening; that character earlier forcibly bathes a child in an attempt to impress the Irish priest Father Mulligan. Two characters in this novel call each other \u201cElvis Pelvis\u201d and \u201cStick Insect,\u201d and one of them is traumatized after being sent out of a showing of The Sound of Music. A character in this novel tells a child that it was actually his evil twin Urumban whom she saw at a rally; that character is later beaten to death by police in the (*) History House. The Oxford scholar Chacko modernizes his family\u2019s company Paradies Pickles in this novel. The \u201cLove Laws\u201d in this novel lead to the deaths of Sophie Mol and the dalit Velutha, with whom Ammu has an affair. The twins Rahel and Estha commit incest at the conclusion of, for 10 points, what debut novel of Arundhati Roy?",
            "answer": "The God of Small Things",
            "subcategory": "Long Fiction",
            "category": "Literature"
        },
        {
            "question": "A friend said this play\u2019s author was in \u201ca funk\u201d after its disastrous premiere in which one actor lost her voice, causing the playwright to hide backstage for the last two acts. Characters play bingo for most of this play\u2019s fourth act, and a character spends most of its third act with a bandage on his head after attempting to shoot himself in the head. An actress says she has no money for her son in this play, then corrects herself but claims she must spend it all on costumes. The poor schoolteacher (*) Medvedenko marries Masha in this play. A reference to the line \u201cIf you ever need my life, come and take it\u201d is engraved on a medallion Nina gives to Trigorin in this play, which takes place on an estate owned by Pyotr Sorin and ends after Konstantin shoots himself. For 10 points, name this play by Anton Chekhov in which Treplev shoots the title bird.",
            "answer": "The Seagull [or Chakya]",
            "subcategory": "Drama",
            "category": "Literature"
        },
        {
            "question": "A character in a story from this country described as \u201cthe butterfly\u201d enters with a \u201csilk petticoat and a kimono jacket\u201d before claiming another character is the \u201cartistic one.\u201d A poem containing the line \u201cWhy must it always be tomato soup?\u201d appears in one story set in this nation describing a husband\u2019s affair with Pearl Fulton. (*) Cream puffs are brought to Scott in one story set in this country, ending with a girl unable to finish the question \u201cIsn\u2019t life-.\u201d This nation is the setting of a story centered around the emotions of Bertha Young titled \u201cBliss,\u201d and of another story in which Laura Sheridan urges her family to cancel the title celebration due to an unexpected death. For 10 points, name this home nation of the author of \u201cThe Garden Party,\u201d Katherine Mansfield.",
            "answer": "New Zealand",
            "subcategory": "Short Fiction",
            "category": "Literature"
        },
        {
            "question": "A character in this work tells another the story of the ancient warrior Meleagar in order to convince him to fight again. The lives of two men are weighed on a scale in this work, and when it is decided which one will die, a character sabotages their battle by appearing disguised as his brother Deiphobos. In this work, the spy Dolon is killed and stripped of his armor while scouting the opposing army; that army is described in the lengthy (*) \u201cCatalogue of Ships.\" A character in this work runs around a wall three times during a battle, and his corpse is later dragged by a chariot in revenge for Patroclus\u2019s death. This work begins in medias res with two warriors fighting over Briseis after Chryseis is sent back to an enemy country. For 10 points, the Trojan Hector dies at the hands of the Greek Achilles in what epic poem by Homer?",
            "answer": "the Iliad",
            "subcategory": "Poetry",
            "category": "Literature"
        },
        {
            "question": "In an essay, this author commented that a different author \u201cgave murder back to the kind of people that commit it.\" A woman uses Lindsay to blackmail Mrs. Florian in a novel by this author, whose protagonist discovers that Ms. Grayle is actually Velma Valento. This author wrote a novel in which Owen Taylor kills a man who runs a pornography racket through a bookstore and takes scandalous pictures of a general\u2019s daughter. In that novel by this author of (*) Farewell, My Lovely, Arthur Geiger blackmails General Sternwood, and the protagonist deduces that the general\u2019s daughter is the true killer of Rusty Regan. This author\u2019s The High Window and The Long Goodbye feature the private detective Philip Marlow. For 10 points, name this author of \u201cThe Simple Art of Murder\u201d and mystery novels such as The Big Sleep.",
            "answer": "Raymond Chandler",
            "subcategory": "Long Fiction",
            "category": "Literature"
        },
        {
            "question": "A character in this play declares that the purpose of acting is \"to create credible situations, in order that they may appear true.\u201d A character in this play lets out a massive wail after one character asks another to remove her mourning frock. One character in this play buys a hat for a prostitute and commits a \u201cvulgar trick,\u201d luring a woman by hanging up hats on pegs. This play ends with the line (*) \u201cI\u2019ve lost a whole day over these people!\u201d after a character\u2019s death is called \u201conly a pretense.\" That character shoots himself with a revolver after another character drowns himself in a fountain. Those characters, the Boy and the Child, are part of the title group who interrupt the Director\u2019s rehearsal of Mixing it Up. For 10 points, name this play about the Mother, the Father, and the Step Daughter, written by Luigi Pirandello.",
            "answer": "Six Characters in Search of an Author [or Sei personaggi in cerca d\u2019autore]",
            "subcategory": "Drama",
            "category": "Literature"
        },
        {
            "question": "A work by this man states that if a more glorious state would have to be established, one can suffer to drop a fruit as fast as it ripened. That essay earlier states that William Paley \u201cappears never to have contemplated those cases to which the rule of expediency does not apply.\" The first section of another work by this man quotes a Chapman poem that mentions \u201crare fires to air\u201d after mentioning a purchase of $3.14 of nails. A work by this author compares voting to \u201ccheckers and backgammon\u201d and discusses his arrest in the (*) Mexican-American War for refusing to pay a poll tax. Another work by this man opens with a section titled \u201cEconomy\u201d and depicts two years he spent living in solitude near the title pond. For 10 points, name this transcendentalist author of \u201cCivil Disobedience\u201d and Walden.",
            "answer": "Henry David Thoreau"
        },
        {
            "question": "In Alan Moore\u2019s Watchmen, a diner named for this character causes Rorschach\u2019s arrest after a note is hidden in one of its trash cans, and it has a large elephant balloon out front. In a poem, a man says, \u201cOr I\u2019ll marrow you this minute,\u201d to threaten this character, who is described as a \u201csquidgy-nosed old idol.\" The speaker of the poem named for this character says, (*) \u201cI shan\u2019t forgit the night\u201d when this character \u201ccarried me away / To where a dooli lay.\u201d This character is described as \u201cLazarushian-leather,\" doesn\u2019t \u201cknow the use o\u2019 fear\u201d in battle, and after rescuing a wounded soldier, that soldier remarks, \u201cYou\u2019re a better man than I am\u201d to him. For 10 points, name this Indian water-boy who is killed after saving an English soldier in a Rudyard Kipling poem.",
            "answer": "Gunga Din [accept either; accept Gunga Diner]",
            "subcategory": "Poetry",
            "category": "Literature"
        },
        {
            "question": "When reporting on the JFK assassination, Sid Davis signed off with this poem\u2019s final lines, which Kennedy often quoted to conclude his campaign speeches. One auditory image in this poem is the \u201csweep / Of easy wind.\u201d The speaker of this poem does not see a farmhouse, but does hear harness bells, assuming his (*) horse is asking \"if there is some mistake.\" The speaker in this poem thinks he might know the man to whom its title location belongs, although he lives \u201cin the village\" far from the title location. This poem likely occurs on the winter solstice, as its speaker notes that it is \"the darkest evening of the year,\" and eventually leaves the title location, for he has \"promises to keep / And miles to go before [he sleeps]\" For 10 points, name this poem by Robert Frost.",
            "answer": "\u201cStopping by Woods on a Snowy Evening\u201d",
            "subcategory": "Poetry",
            "category": "Literature"
        },
        {
            "question": "A novel by this author sees the lawyer Galip search for his wife Ruya and brother-in-law Celal, before finding them shot at an Aladdin store. Hasan beheads one character in another novel by this author after he sees his ruby-studded dagger in that character\u2019s hands. The protagonist of that novel is in love with Shekure and helps Enishte write a secret book. In another novel by this author, the protagonist observes the death of the Director of the Institute of Education while sitting at New Life Caf\u00e9 with his lover. In addition to (*) The Black Book, this author wrote a novel in which Zaim is murdered by Kadife during a performance of The Spanish Tragedy by Thomas Kyd. The author Ka betrays the Muslim extremist Blue, who was the former lover of Ipek, in one novel by this author. For 10 points, name this Turkish author of My Name is Red and Snow.",
            "answer": "Orhan Pamuk",
            "subcategory": "Long Fiction",
            "category": "Literature"
        },
        {
            "question": "Two characters in this novel are described as smelling \u201clike a broom\u201d after the protagonist helps pay for a bicycle. This novel\u2019s protagonist is given fancy shoes in a chapter titled \u201cThe Family of Little Feet,\u201d after which another character is offered a kiss for a dollar. That protagonist is pushed into an open fire hydrant and is later told her fortune by \u201cThe Three Sisters\u201d at a deceased baby\u2019s wake in this novel. The protagonist of this novel is sexually assaulted after being abandoned at a display of red clowns at a (*) carnival, and later learns that her friend Sally is abused by her father and husband. This novel\u2019s protagonist wishes her name could be \u201cZeze the X,\u201d and she lives with her sister Nenny in a Chicago barrio. For 10 points, name this novel centered on Esperanza Cordero by Sandra Cisneros.",
            "answer": "The House on Mango Street",
            "subcategory": "Long Fiction",
            "category": "Literature"
        },
        {
            "question": "In one story by this author, Maria takes a sleigh to a village church to wait for her lover. The protagonist of one story by this author sends love letters to Lizavyeta to learn the secret of the Count of St. Germain. The protagonist of one novel by this author advises another character temper her love in his namesake \u201cSermon.\u201d In a story by this author, Masha falls in love with (*) Burmin, which leads him to confess his earlier prank to marry a bride during the title event. Hermann is committed to a mental asylum after losing all his money on the title card, which eerily looks like the Countess, in one story by this author. The title character of one novel by this author kills Lensky in a duel after Lensky invites him to Tatyana\u2019s name day celebration. For 10 points, name this Russian author of \u201cThe Blizzard,\u201d \u201cThe Queen of Spades,\u201d and Eugene Onegin.",
            "answer": "Alexander Pushkin",
            "subcategory": "Short Fiction",
            "category": "Literature"
        },
        {
            "question": "The second one of these characters is said to look like \u201cthe change of life\u201d while naked after insulting a character for incorrectly cutting tobacco. That one of these characters is introduced while the first of these people is out buying a mule to do manual labor. The first of these characters is introduced after the protagonist kisses Johnny Taylor under a blossoming (*) pear tree. One of these people is described as having a \u201cbig voice\u201d while becoming the mayor of a growing city, and the third and final of these people is an avid gambler who is shot and killed by the main character after contracting rabies from a dog in a hurricane. For 10 points, name this relation held by Logan Killicks, Jody Starks, and Tea Cake to the protagonist of Their Eyes Were Watching God by Zora Neale Hurston.",
            "answer": "husband of Janie Crawford [accept spouse for husband; accept either name for Janie; generously prompt on characters in Their Eyes Were Watching God; prompt on the first or last name of Logan Killicks, Jody Starks, or Tea Cake]",
            "subcategory": "Long Fiction",
            "category": "Literature"
        },
        {
            "question": "Freidrich Nietzche\u2019s \u00dcbermensch was inspired heavily by this man\u2019s characters, specifically one who complains of Spain\u2019s destruction by French invaders. That character fights in the Battle of Waterloo before travelling to Switzerland and lamenting the changes in Venetian beauty as a result of war. The title character of a poem by this man becomes friends with Catherine the Great and is sold as a slave in (*) Constantinople. In another poem by this man, the subject, described as \u201cSo soft, so calm, yet eloquent,\u201d does the title action \u201clike the night / Of cloudless climes and starry skies.\u201d For 10 points, name this poet-turned-revolutionary, who died in the Greek War of Independence after writing Childe Harold\u2019s Pilgrimage, Don Juan, and \u201cShe Walks in Beauty.\u201d",
            "answer": "Lord Byron [or George Gordon Byron]",
            "subcategory": "Poetry",
            "category": "Literature"
        },
        {
            "question": "In this collection, Doctor Parcival asserts that \u201ceveryone in the world is Christ and they are all crucified.\u201d A character in this collection consoles his wife by reading pieces of paper that were placed in his deep pockets. A reverend in this collection punches his hand through a window when he observes a character praying while (*) naked. The main character of this collection fails to recognize the sexual tension between him and Kate Swift in the story \u201cThe Teacher.\u201d One character in this collection flees from Pennsylvania to the title location after being accused of molesting a student. George Willard leaves this collection\u2019s title location in \u201cDeparture\u201d; that location is also home to Wing Biddlebaum. For 10 points, name this collection of short stories including \u201cThe Book of the Grotesque\u201d and \u201cHands\u201d by Sherwood Anderson.",
            "answer": "Winesburg, Ohio",
            "subcategory": "Short Fiction",
            "category": "Literature"
        },
        {
            "question": "This character has an album full of clippings he likes, one of which is a Kruschen Salts ad. This character, who believes that God is a waste of time, is taught to spray water by a man who planned to spit in his girlfriend\u2019s face to get revenge. This character is shown a small, silver crucifix by a man who asks him if he lives with the idea that nothing will remain after he dies. This man notices his mother\u2019s \u201cfianc\u00e9\u201d (*) Thomas P\u00e9rez falling behind during a funeral procession at which this character smokes and drinks coffee in front of a coffin. This man commits a violent action at 2 P.M. that he blames on the bright sun. For 10 points, name this character who is sentenced to death for killing an Arab, the protagonist of Albert Camus\u2019s The Stranger.",
            "answer": "Meursault [prompt on The Stranger or L'\u00c9tranger before mention]",
            "subcategory": "Long Fiction",
            "category": "Literature"
        },
        {
            "question": "The protagonist of a novel by this author curses the end of a war by saying \u201clet the darkness of my heart\u2026 equal the darkness of the night.\u201d In another novel by this author, the protagonist is told by his nurse that a picture of a European knight is one of Joan of Arc. A drunk American soldier in a novel by this author asks the protagonist to trample on the stomach of his pregnant wife. The homosexual (*) Kochan admires the body of Omi and fails to love Sonoko in one novel by this author. In another novel by this author, Kashiwagi boasts that women \u201cfall in love with his clubfeet.\u201d Mizoguchi sets the title location on fire at the end of that novel by this author. For 10 points, name this Japanese author of Confessions of a Mask and Temple of the Golden Pavilion.",
            "answer": "Yukio Mishima [or Kimitake Hiraoka; accept names in either order]",
            "subcategory": "Long Fiction",
            "category": "Literature"
        },
        {
            "question": "After this character hesitates about her doings, another exclaims \u201cDeception? Deception?\u201d while returning from a D.A.R meeting. This character explains that music is coming from the Paradise Dance Hall and admits she spent time at the zoo rather than attending Rubicam College. This character her former classmate reminisce about a particular write up for The Torch and about a lead role in The (*) Pirates of Penzance. A bout of pleurosis led one character to nickname this woman \u201cBlue Roses.\u201d The play this character appears in ends with her blowing the candles out, while earlier she is heartbroken to learn that her former high school crush is engaged after a unicorn figurine loses its horn. For 10 points, name this sister of Tom Wingfield, a central character in Tennessee Williams\u2019 The Glass Menagerie.",
            "answer": "Laura Wingfield [prompt on Wingfield until read]",
            "subcategory": "Drama",
            "category": "Literature"
        },
        {
            "question": "Two characters created by this author play a game of checkers with miniature scotch bottles, and drink each piece after it\u2019s taken. A character in a novel by this author stays with Mr. Tench but misses his boat after tending to a dying woman. Carter poisons the protagonist\u2019s drink in a novel by this author, and shoots Dr. Hasselbacher after a dachshund drinks it. After determining that the (*) \u201cmestizo\u201d is untrustworthy, the protagonist of a novel by this author decides not to go to Carmen. Beatrice Severn is moved to Jakarta after serving as the secretary for the vacuum-cleaner salesman-turned-spy James Wormold in a novel by this author. Another novel by this writer is set in a Mexican state where religion is outlawed, leading the \u201clieutenant\u201d to chase after the \u201cwhiskey priest.\u201d For 10 points, name this author of Our Man in Havana and The Power and the Glory.",
            "answer": "Graham Greene",
            "subcategory": "Long Fiction",
            "category": "Literature"
        }
    ],
    "bonuses": []
}